inchcalculator.com 2019-12-27

# Privacy Policy - Inch Calculator

At inchcalculator.com we consider the privacy of our visitors to be extremely important. This privacy policy document describes in detail the types of personal information is collected and recorded by inchcalculator.com and how we use it. 

## Log Files

Like many other Web sites, inchcalculator.com makes use of log files. These files merely logs visitors to the site – usually a standard procedure for hosting companies and a part of hosting services’s analytics. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and possibly the number of clicks. This information is used to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. 

## Cookies and Web Beacons

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Inchcalculator and our partners (such as advertising, marketing and analytics), affiliates or analytics or service providers. These technologies may be used in analyzing trends, administering the Sites, tracking users’ movements around the Sites and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by such companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. Our partners may also use such technologies to deliver advertisements to you as described below. While we respect the privacy of our users, we are not able to respond to Do Not Track signals set by your browser at this time. 

## Hotjar

We use [Hotjar](http://www.hotjar.com/) in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices (in particular device’s IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy).

You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this [opt-out link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out). 

## DoubleClick DART Cookie

→ Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on inchcalculator.com.  
→ Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our site’s visitors based upon their visit to inchcalculator.com and other sites on the Internet.  
→ Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

## Our Advertising Partners

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include:

  * Google
  * Amazon
  * Networx

Please consult these advertising partner’s privacy policies for their sites. 

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology in their respective advertisements and links that appear on inchcalculator.com and which are sent directly to your browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by our site’s third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertising campaigns and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see on the site.  
inchcalculator.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. 

Inchcalculator.com is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com. 

## Third Party Privacy Policies

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. inchcalculator.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites. You may find a comprehensive listing of these privacy policies and their links here: Privacy Policy Links.  
If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites. 

## Children’s Information

We believe it is important to provide added protection for children online. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children to observe, participate in and/or monitor and guide their online activity. inchcalculator.com does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If a parent or guardian believes that inchcalculator.com has in its database the personally-identifiable information of a child under the age of 13, please contact us immediately (using the contact in the final paragraph) and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records. 

## Online Privacy Policy Only

This privacy policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our website and regarding information shared and/or collected there. This policy does not apply to any information collected offline or via channels other than this website. 

## Consent

By using our website, you hereby consent to our privacy policy and agree to its terms. 

## Update

This Privacy Policy was last updated on: November 7th, 2019.  
Should we update, amend or make any changes to our privacy policy, those changes will be posted here. 

Please contact us with all questions and concerns.
